Guide to the Tro Harper Photographs of Stanford Student Life
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Tro Harper photographs of Stanford student life
1935-1940
PC0116
Harper, Tro.
1 Linear feet
Collection largely consists of negatives 1935-37, a few contemporary prints, and contact sheets from selected negative rolls made in 1988. Subjects include rehearsals for student plays, parties and excursions, Prof. Thomas Bailey in class, exams, 1936 graduation, campus scenes, and individuals and groups of students. Collection also includes a small amount of correspondence, 1938-40, and miscellaneous financial documents.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Frederick Troman (Tro) Harper earned his AB in social sciences at Stanford University in 1937. He owned and operated Tro Harper, Books in San Francisco. He was a member of The Bohemian Club and the San Francisco Golf Club.
Description of the Collection
Collection largely consists of negatives 1935-37, a few contemporary prints, and contact sheets from selected negative rolls made in 1988. Subjects include rehearsals for student plays, parties and excursions, Prof. Thomas Bailey in class, exams, 1936 graduation, campus scenes, and individuals and groups of students. Collection also includes a small amount of correspondence, 1938-40, and miscellaneous financial documents.
Access Terms
Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-1983.; Harper, Tro.
Collection Contents
- Photographs, 1935-1940
  - Contact sheet, roll A2, with print of one image (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Contact sheet, roll A5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contact sheet, roll A8, with print of one image (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contact sheet, roll A11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contact sheet, roll A19, with print of one image (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Contact sheet, roll G2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Contact sheet, roll G6, with print of one image (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Contact sheet, roll G9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contact sheet, roll G15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contact sheet, roll G16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Contact sheet, roll S1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Contact sheet, roll S2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Contact sheet, roll S3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Contact sheet, roll S4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Contact sheet, roll S5 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Contact sheet, roll S6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Contemporary prints (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Memorial Church images--negatives only (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Golden Gate Bridge--2 images, negatives and prints (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Original envelopes (Stanford Quad letterhead) for S1-S6 negatives (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous financial documents (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - original index cards on film rolls (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Negatives, roll A2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Negatives, roll A5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Negatives, roll A8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Negatives, roll A11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Negatives, roll A19 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Negatives, roll G2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Negatives, roll G6 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Negatives, roll G9 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Negatives, roll G15 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, roll G16 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Negatives, roll S1, 1936 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Negatives, roll S2, 1936 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Negatives, roll S3, 1936 June 21 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Negatives, roll S4, 1936 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Negatives, roll S5, 1936 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Negatives, roll S6, 1936 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Remaining negative rolls (in original cans) (Box 3)
Index of Subjects by Roll
A1 Candids of Brown (H.C.), Allaga, Ettlinger, Rosemary, Drysdale, Cottril, Slusser
A2 Mac at Phelps, Mrs. Bacon, Santa Cruz over the fourth of July
A3 Ernie; Mrs. Dougherty; George Hatch; Library shots of pillars; Langstroff
A4 Sausalito; Bulloch; Pratt; Fisherman's wharf; San Francisco from Russian Hill; Amelia Baines working on costume; Amelia and Gist
A5 Candids of [Thomas] Bailey in history class; Antony and Cleopatra in rehearsal
A6 Stage Classics Workshop pix
A7 Antony and Cleopatra in rehearsal (2nd pix)
A8 Caesar and Cleopatra in rehearsal in the women's gym; Onyet Watson and cig
A9 Typewriter; Ed and Carl Abbott on golf course; me; Ed
A10 Ed; Phyllis Corson; Onyet; Betty Butcher; Bay Bridge; Shots on stage at Golden Gat NG
A11 Dress rehearsal of Caesar and Cleopatra, Marge Bailey, Phyllis Corson, Onyet Watson (summer 1936)
A12 Gilman Gist modeling; Phelps-Terkel; Mac at Phelps; trees in arboretum (Aug. 27, 1936
A15 Portraits of me, Weaver; Illustrated Review cover of Union (Oct. 1936)
A19 Beer Bust with Cal (October 1936)
A25 Antony and Cleopatra in final rehearsal
G1 Exams (pix taken for LIFE--no sale), Eisenbach & Johnson Hill
G2 Exams, girl asleep, Middletown, campus shots
G3 Easter vacation 1937; Johnson Hill, Shirley Jones, Marjorie Hallohan, Tro Harper, Helen Zwick, Donna Evans, Bettye Faus, Hunt Kingsbury, Tom Spivey
G4 Easter vacation at Bass Lake; Bettye and Onyet, poker game, snow shots
G5 End of Easter vacation 1937; Ettlinger at home, Leah Ray, Sophia, Bettye on lot, Leah on set, Fox lot, Onyet in makeup
G6 Bettye climbs fence, Loupe, fire in San Francisco, rescue shots, pole vault, track meet, Ben Eastman and brother, Templeton, Peterson and Klaube
G7 Eisenbach, Seid, Frost, red filter shots of campus (April 10, 1937)
G8 Shots taken at Holy City, Calif. in preparation for an article for LIFE (April 11, 1937)
G9 Shots of Bettye Faus, track pictures of McCurdy etc. for layouts in Daily, also baseball, Dink Templeton
G10 Operation pix (April 18, 1937)
G11 Hospital pix for Ballard
G12 Campus shots taken for Ballard's brochure (April 1937)
G13 Rehearsal shots of "Down the Hatch", track meet USC
G14 Weigle and farmer in class; Zwick in class; Brownell; Kales; McDaniel-- world's record vault; new theater
G15 Lutz in class, patterns in tiles, Art Dept.
G16 Nitery, Farm shots, women's pool and archery, Chi Omega house (Spring 1937)
G17 In Stanford chem. lab; Bettye; Phil Kuhn; makeup room for "Down the Hatch"
G18 L.P. Gebhardt at Stanford in connection with infantile stuff for California; after the party pix (Spring 1937)
S1 The Flower Lady, Mrs. Coverly, Mrs. Croak in the lower division office, loud George--6/20/36
S2 Dorothy Gaff, Figureheads in Memorial Court, Copey, RR joint-- 6/18/36
S3 Ted Turlow, Paul Thurlow, shots taken from Olsen and Johnson-- 6/21/36
S4 Life Saver, lights and shadows, Brown (Phil and H. W.), fire, Jack at Beltramos, Ballard, Weigle, Farmer, Ettiene, Ted at Phelps--6/26/36
S5 Graduation, night pictures at the Mark--6/17/36
S6 Dorothy Gaff, sectional trials, Tiny Thornhill, Gordon Davis, Bob Bacon --6/14/36
#34 Graduation exercises; Onyet; Weaver and father; Beta class; Beta House comes down (June 1937